{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following microorganisms leach metals out of rock ores and can accumulate silver?", "opta": "Pseudomonas aeruginosa", "optb": "Thiobacillus", "optc": "Pseudomonas putida", "optd": "Zoogloea ramigera", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Inundation involves use of a/an", "opta": "large number of organisms over a short time to suppress/destroy a population", "optb": "organism over a short time to suppress/destroy a population", "optc": "large number of organisms over a long time to suppress/destroy a population", "optd": "organism over a long time to suppress/destroy a population", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Milbemycin is known to exhibit a broad spectrum of activity against", "opta": "agricultural pests", "optb": "agricultural herbs", "optc": "agricultural insects", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rate of degradation and microbes resistance to toxic pollutants remain better when the", "opta": "mixed cell population is used", "optb": "individual cell is used", "optc": "mixed cell population along with metals is used", "optd": "individual cell along with metal is used", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the bacteria is considered for biological leaching?", "opta": "T. thiooxidans", "optb": "T. ferrooxidans", "optc": "Ferrobacillus terrooxidans", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The heavily polluted zone of water reservoir is known as", "opta": "pleosaprophytic zone", "optb": "mesosaprophytic zone", "optc": "oligosaprophytic zone", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Streptomyces griseochromogenes is reported to show a potent curative effect against", "opta": "rice blast disease", "optb": "yellow blight of maize", "optc": "milo of soybean", "optd": "eye spot of sugarcane", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is selectively effective against dicot weeds?", "opta": "Cycloheximide", "optb": "Anisomycin", "optc": "Herbicidin A and B", "optd": "Bialaphos", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following/(s) can be used for the reduction of nitrate in waste water?", "opta": "Growth of Hypomicrobium in presence of added methanol", "optb": "Micrococcus denitrificans cells encapsulated in liquid membranes", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Nitrosomonas europaen", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following herbicide is known to be effective against perennial shrubs, annual weeds and weeds of rice?", "opta": "Cycloheximide", "optb": "Anisomycin", "optc": "Herbicidin", "optd": "Bialaphos", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is known to control Colorado potato beetle?", "opta": "Beaveria bassiana", "optb": "Metarhizium anisopliae", "optc": "Verticillium lecauii", "optd": "Nomuraea rileyi", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phenols degradation in waste water of hospitals, laboratories and coal processing to coke can be achieved by using", "opta": "fungus Aureobasidium pullulans adsorbed by the fibrous asbestos", "optb": "cells of Pseudomonas spp. either adsorbed to anthracite coal or entrapped on alginate gel", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Phanerochaete chrysosporium", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the most effective for the rice sheath blight pathogen, Pellicularia sasakii?", "opta": "Polyoxin D", "optb": "Polyoxin B", "optc": "Polyoxin L", "optd": "Polyoxin C", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following subgroup/(s) belong/(s) to the Baculo viruses?", "opta": "Nuclear polyhedrosis viruses", "optb": "Granulosis viruses", "optc": "Oryctestypes", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following accumulates from factory waste?", "opta": "Pseudomonas aeruginosa", "optb": "Thiobacillus", "optc": "Pseudomonas putida", "optd": "Zoogloea ramigera", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following can be used for the removal of color from the effluents of pulp mill?", "opta": "Coriolus versicolor entrapped in calcium alginate beads", "optb": "Phanerochaete chrysosporium", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Nitrosomonas europaen", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following have been used to oxidize ammonia and to prevent algal growth?", "opta": "growth of hypomicrobium in presence of added methanol", "optb": "Micrococcus denitrificans cells encapsulated in liquid membranes", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Nitrosomonas europaen", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}